KUNAL BODKE

User Experience Designer

Portfolio: kunal.design Phone: **317.760.1611**

Email: kunalbodke1@gmail.com

As a UX Designer with 2+ years of experience, I can harness my skills and become a valuable player in a design team. I use **contextual inquiry**, **user interviews** and **personas** to extract pain points. I turn complex problems into simple flows with rapid sketching and iteration. My work spans across web, desktops and mobile applications for both iOS and Android platforms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX Designer at Regenstrief Institute, Inc June 2016 - present

Lead participatory design session, contextual interviews and card-sorting sessions to understand end users. Design physical and digital products to aid older adults. Sketch, create wireframes, and prototype to test concepts and ideas with potential users. Collaborate with stakeholders to brainstorm on personas, and understand the problem space.

UX Consultant at WEDO Charity Auctions, LLC Sept 2016 - present

Increased website's conversation rates by 53% with new design workflow. Currently, identifying easy-to-fix usability issues by conducting a cognitive walkthrough and heuristic review. Restructure information presented to the users to improve efficiency and reduce errors. Create user flows with documentation to ensure cohesive product output.

UX Design Intern at NOMI Beauty Feb 2016 - May 2016

Designed and prototyped a mobile app from paper to a final product. Analyzed existing competitive products and adopted successful design patterns. Followed iOS design guidelines to craft a seamless user experience. Gathered feedback from potential users based on specific tasks. Co-ordinated with product manager and CTO to design features in Lean UX fashion.

UX Researcher at Health Innovation Lab, IUPUI May 2015 - May 2016

Created a simplified tablet interface for patients suffering from cognitive decline. Nine contextual inquiry sessions with clinic staff and patients to understand the problem space. Designed and created a functional prototype using HTML/CSS on an Android tablet. Conducted 3 rounds of usability tests with 15+ end users.

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Awards

- Best-in-show award for Master's Capstone project in May 2016
- IUPUI Merit based scholarship and research assistantship 2014-2016

Memberships

- American Medical Informatics Association (AMIA) 2016-present
- Human Factors and Ergnomics Society (HFES) 2016

SKILLS

Research

Contextual Inquiry
User Interviews
Journey Maps
Personas and Scenarios
Heuristic Evaluation
Cognitive Walkthrough
Usability Testing
Personas

Design

User flows
Wireframes
Storyboards
Prototyping
iOS and Android Design
Information Architecture
HTML/CSS/Javascript

Tools

Sketch
Axure
Principle
Invision
Marvel
Adobe Illustrator
Keynote

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction

Indiana University, Indianapolis. Aug 2014 – May 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

University of Pune, India. Sept 2009 - June 2012